Farewell, Earth
The ship that is departing is
The Space Battleship
Yamato
It departs now to Iscandar,
at the end of the cosmos,
bearing its fate.
"We will come back, no matter what it takes"
Answer with a smile to the waving people
Going far from the Galaxy towards Iscandar
A faint gleam of hope
The Space Battleship Yamato
Garmillas
Beloved citizens of the Great Garmillas Empire,
I know the crown of glory on my head is a gift made possible by your loyalty
to the nation and to this planet, to Great Garmillas.
I name you my friends,
and I am grateful to all of you for gathering here today.
Thank you.
Ghale Garmillon! Ghale Desler!
Ilun Phuzeron.
You wrote a good speech.
You honor me.
Humans are foolish and submissive creatures.
And more than anything, they bore me.
Your post-speech entertainment is ready.
Miezela Celestella
Propaganda Minister
That ship?
Yes.
Lord Abelt Desler
Your Lordship,
Vice-Commander Redof Hyss
on behalf of your staff, I congratulate you on the 1000 years of Garmillas history,
as well as the 103rd year of your reign.
Thank you, Vice-Commander.
The Great Garmillas Empire
has succeeded in uniting both the
Large and Small Magellanic Clouds,
and has expanded into the Milky Way.
The Empire's territory continues to expand,
and your glory shines down, across the entire universe.
Our unification policy is working, as well.
Velte Talan
Armaments Minister
Those that submit to us are allowed to contribute to the Empire
as second-class Garmillans, rather than be destroyed.
Truly a mighty deed!
Truly the act of a god.
No enemy can
withstand the might of His Lordship and the Great Garmillas armies!
Herm Zoellik
Inspector-General of the Central Army
Garmillas is invincible! We will never be defeated!
Arrogance is a mistake.
We must remain wary of
Gul Ditz
Supreme Commander of Astrofleets
the barbarian invaders from outside the galaxy around the Small Magellanic Cloud.
Admiral Ditz!
Are you calling me a boaster?
As the Commander of the Astrofleets, I speak the truth.
Ghader Talan
Vice-Chief of the General Staff
Your Lordship,
we will eliminate these barbarians soon.
I've dispatched Senior General Domel.
The Space Wolf?
I'm sure he will live up to our expectations.
Everyone, I've prepared some entertainment to help you
forget the stress of your difficult jobs.
Tonight, you will watch video from the front lines of the Empire's war.
Heydom Gimleh
Imperial Guard Information Officer
Why would we watch that?
Because His Lordship created the plan you are about to see in execution.
Very well, everyone, let us begin the game.
When you wish upon a star,
if your heart is in your dream,
no request is too extreme,
when you wish upon a star as dreamers do.
Like a bolt out of the blue, fate will come, and see you through.
YRA Radio Yamato.
Our next broadcast will be at 20:30 local time.
This has been Yuria Misaki.
And that's a wrap.
Are you sure it's okay for you to kill time here?
Yeah, I'm off now.
Hey, did you know...
There's a door up here that never opens.
And supposedly, a ghost is there. The ghost of a beautiful woman.
It just suddenly appears—
I saw that all the time on Earth.
I see those things.
You do?
The Yamato is currently around 8 light years from Earth,
traversing the Sirius System at 18 s-knots.
We'll be jumping 12 light years in our next warp.
That should take us to Gliese 581.
12 light years?
This will be our last chance to see Earth through the Yamato's VLBI telescope.
Sanada.
Yes, sir.
Is that...
...the Earth?
We are 8.6 light years from the Solar System.
In other words, this is how Earth looked eight years ago.
Before Garmillas attacked it?
Everyone, look well.
This is Earth as it used to be, the Earth we're fighting to reclaim.
Shima, prepare for warp.
Roger. Preparing for warp.
Yamato has jumped.
ID the jump coordinates.
Beginning space-time wave motion calculations.
Tracing space wake.
Rear Brigadier!
Friendly resupply ship requests a rendezvous.
Daddy, finish your work soon, and come home, okay?
Mom's worried...
Lord Desler ordered us to fight and die.
I'm sorry, Hilde.
Commander Schultz, General Goer's resupply has arrived.
No way... Is that true?
Yes, we were not abandoned, after all!
Garemud Goer
Galactic Theater Commander
Galactic Theater Commander Goer, sir!
I am honored to be the commanding officer for the operation Your Lordship designed.
That's enough.
Goer, what became of the thing I sent you?
Yes, sir! I'm sorry! The new torpedo...
The Desler Torpedo...
Yes, the Desler Torpedo!
We have already deployed it on the front lines.
Warp complete.
We are in the Gliese 581 System.
We are 20.4 light years from the Earth.
That's the primary star, Gliese 581, a red dwarf star.
Looks like the warp hasn't had any negative effects.
But be careful.
This is Intelligence Officer Niimi. I'm coming in.
Okay, take care.
We'll be going, then.
Is this a good time?
It's fine.
What is it?
This system has a planet suitable for the human-colonization plan.
I'd like permission to form an expedition to investigate it.
We don't have the time.
Of course that's true, but...
But don't we need all possible options, if humanity is going to survive?
Niimi, the Izumo Plan was scrapped.
But that was...
Port side has been hit.
Righting the ship. Tilting fifteen degrees.
Some electronics are off line.
Detecting a powerful charged-particle wave motion.
Ahead slow. Red 20!
What is this?
Report!
It seems we've run into a hyper-dense plasma filament field.
What are those?
Plasma flares being emitted by a star.
A solar storm, in other words.
Our ship has run into the edge of one of the plasma corridors.
But this isn't normal.
Birkeland currents are several hundred million times their theoretical values.
What does that mean?
It means this has clearly been artificially created.
The rat has fallen into the trap!
I, Goer, am terribly impressed that you
predicted they would come to this system!
It's nothing. I thought it might be amusing to analyze their ship's course.
The fun is just beginning.
Everyone, let us have a toast to cheer our Terron friends on.
Hilarious!
Set a trap for them, and then cheer them on?
Your Lordship does enjoy his jokes!
Garmillas has no need of such disgusting men.
Ghale Desler!
Hail to our Leader!
I have electronics back on line.
But we won't be able to contact them too many times.
Calculate the range of plasma amplification.
Find a weak point in the corridor.
It should be somewhere out there.
Plasma gets weaker at three o'clock.
It's probably a weak spot.
There's a distortion in the gravity field, to our rear.
Something's warping out.
Torpedo loaded!
Fire the Desler Torpedo!
Enemy ship has fired a torpedo!
20 seconds until out of interception range.
Locked.
AA System ready.
Ready to intercept torpedo.
13 seconds.
Prepare to intercept.
Time until out of interception range:
10... 9... 8... 7...
Captain!
6... 5... 4... 3...
Open the firing tubes along the ship's stern!
2... 1...
Fire!
Hit. We've intercepted the target.
Wait a moment!
What's this?
What is this?
Sending video to Imperial Command.
Did you see that? That is the Desler Torpedo.
Is that gas?
Originating in the Mirbelia System,
it is an autonomous, self-replicating gas-based life form.
It converts, unites, and absorbs material energy, enabling indefinite expansion.
The ultimate in chemical weapons.
I threw a cat into the rat trap.
Unidentified object's energy readings are rising.
Keep an eye on it.
It's absorbing the plasma and growing.
If we come into contact with it,
we'll be broken down and absorbed.
The unidentified object is approaching us.
Just like a rat in a trap, indeed.
Now we just wait for the cat to kill it.
No, I've prepared an exit for them.
Shima, can we make it through that
weak point you found in the plasma?
I believe so.
Wait.
If we keep going, through that area...
No way.
However, a giant star waits, mouth open, at the exit.
Will they be consumed by gas or
disintegrated in a burning fusion reactor?
Or is there another fate for them?
No other, of course. It is perfect, Your Lordship.
Everyone, let us applaud the brave decision they're about to make.
We can't go forward or back, can we?
Shima, full speed ahead, toward the star.
Are we going to ram into the star?
Full speed ahead! Steady as she goes!
It appears the Terrons have chosen to commit suicide by fire.
Temperature outside the ship is 1100 degrees.
Inside, 90 degrees and rising!
Environmental control systems unable to moderate the temperature.
Captain, why don't we engage the Wave Motion Shield?
At this rate, the ship's temperature will exceed the limit.
There's no need.
Everyone, put on your environmental suits.
Keep energy expenditure to a minimum as we advance.
Seal the bulkheads.
What about the Garmillas ship?
It's 8000 behind the gas. It's following us.
Keep a close eye on it.
Captain!
All crew, put on your environmental suits.
Oh, no!
Doctor, you need to put this on!
Repeat: All crew, put on your environmental suits.
Captain!
Why the heck are we running toward that?!
Turn us around now!
Are you trying to get the captain killed?
It's okay.
My old wounds are just bothering me a little.
Right, Doctor?
Well, let me have a look, just to be on the safe side...
Pulse is normal.
No problems at all!
Just some work-induced fatigue...
Guess I'll give you a nutrient injection.
Good.
I've been asked to keep you alive!
You need to listen to my orders.
Your condition...
I'm well aware, Doctor.
Solar prominence straight ahead, at SK223.
Steer to port.
Captain, there's a change in the gas behind us!
It's trying to absorb the star, and it's being absorbed in turn.
I see... So this is what the captain was after, right?
You incompetents!
Were you just sitting and watching,
as His Lordship's gas was devoured?
You useless, inferior races!
The entire responsibility for this rests with you, okay?
You'd better believe I'll be reporting that to His Lordship!
This ship will now make a final run at the Yamato.
We go with Brigadier Schultz!
Something's happened! A massive flare in front of us!
Can't we dodge it, Shima?
No, it's too big. We can't evade it!
Maintain course.
Kodai, hit the flare with the Wave Motion Gun.
Yes, sir.
Hit the flare?
Repeat that order!
Y-Yes, sir!
We'll hit the flare with the Wave Motion Gun.
Opening circuit to Wave Motion Gun.
Shutting all emergency valves.
Releasing safety lock.
Activating force injector.
Tachyon particle pressure rising in chamber.
80%.
85%.
90%.
Enemy ship rapidly approaching behind us!
Hit to starboard!
Ignore them!
Ten seconds before we're too close!
Energy charge 120%!
Firing Wave Motion Gun!
Head straight through that opening. Maintain course!
Yamato has broken through the solar prominence!
Ship temperature is 3,000,000 bek!
Impossible!
Our ship can't handle this heat!
Stern is melting.
We've lost control!
Glory to Zaltz!
Video signal lost.
Your Lordship! All responsibility for this failure rests with Schultz...
And I...
Was that not a splendid battle, everyone?
It was quite an entertaining game.
Hyss...
Sir!
The dead are to be awarded a two-rank promotion.
Give their families honorary Garmillan status.
Zar Belk!
That will be all for this evening.
Good night, everyone.
Ghale Desler!
Oh, one more thing, Celestella...
What was the Terron ship's name?
I believe it was called the "Yamato."
The Yamato?
I shall remember that.
What's wrong?
That weapon that broke through the flare...
It's similar to the prototype that
Weapons Development is working on.
Is that true, Velte?
Impossible.
Let's wish upon a star again tonight.
Trust our wishes to the stars, like dreamers do.
When you wish upon a star,
your dreams come true.
This has been Yuria Misaki.
Episode 8
Wish Upon a Star
That girl was waving
A bright red scarf
Who do you think it was for?
Whoever it was
It doesn’t matter
Let each think it was for him
The hearts of men beginning a journey
Want a piece of romance
A bright red scarf
Garmilloids are the Garmillas's vanguard.
Are the words spoken by the one we captured the truth, or falsehood?
Does the answer lie beyond communication between machines?
What is a person? What is a machine? And, what is a heart?
Next time: Clockwork Prisoner.
There are 339 days left before humanity is extinct.